<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on AriezLabs</title>
    <link>https://ariezlabs.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on AriezLabs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 16:58:53 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ariezlabs.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linux on a Convertible, Round 2</title>
      <link>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/x390/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 21:21:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/x390/</guid>
      <description>Preamble In my Setups post, I mentioned that I used to use a ThinkPad X390 Yoga as my main workhorse. I was hoping that a convertible laptop could replace both my aging MacBook and iPad; as it turned out the software wasn&amp;rsquo;t ready yet and it was a pretty shitty experience overall. Next thing, Covid happened, and being stuck at home, I switched to a desktop Hackintosh plus an iPad Pro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualization</title>
      <link>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 11:40:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/virtualization/</guid>
      <description>This week I&amp;rsquo;ve played around with virtualization a bit. I wanna give a high level overview of the project first, and then dive into a few details.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently using a i7-6700, 16GB RAM, Radeon RX570 Hackintosh and the goal was running both a virtualized Windows and macOS on that machine simultaneously, using Linux as host. The RX570 would be passed through to the Windows VM for gaming, with macOS getting the iGPU as &amp;ldquo;work OS&amp;rdquo; and Linux just running headless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lockdown Lifestyle</title>
      <link>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/covid_routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 22:00:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/covid_routine/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been almost exactly a year since COVID got real and so I thought I would write a bit on how my and my girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s life has been throughout the pandemic. This is going to be kind of a snapshot since things are changing all the time, but I think it&amp;rsquo;ll be nice to look back at this at some point into the future where life has hopefully returned to normal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fried Buldak</title>
      <link>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/friedbuldak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 12:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/friedbuldak/</guid>
      <description>This recipe combines two of my favorite meals ever: fried chicken and Buldak, Korean fire chicken. It&amp;rsquo;s based on Serious Eat&amp;rsquo;s Buldak sauce and Quang Tran&amp;rsquo;s Sriracha Fried Chicken.
This is the first recipe I (in part) created on my own that&amp;rsquo;s so good I&amp;rsquo;m confident enough to share it. 😉 If you like fried chicken and spicy food, you&amp;rsquo;re going to love this.
Ingredients For one serving.
Buldak sauce:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi Zero</title>
      <link>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 20:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/zero/</guid>
      <description>Updated Feb 22: details and clarification
So last week I bought a Pi Zero hoping it could replace the AWS EC2 instance that I currently use as a SSH server for my iPad Pro. I use this to do actual programming work on the iPad, and overall, I&amp;rsquo;m pretty happy with this setup even though it&amp;rsquo;s got a few warts.
 My motivation for going with a local SSH server is mostly in not being dependent on a decent internet connection, though price, control and ping are upsides as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Lab pt.3</title>
      <link>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/homelab3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 17:49:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/homelab3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m generifying the title of this series, because with the latest addition, the lab&amp;rsquo;s not just a Mac Mini anymore. I&amp;rsquo;ve dusted off my Raspberry Pi, which I habitually do, roughly every couple of months, intending to start some project until interest wanes about two weeks later and the Pi goes back on the shelf. This time I&amp;rsquo;ve hooked it up to my TV and installed RPiPlay, and I&amp;rsquo;ve got a feeling that the Pi has finally found a good home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac Mini Home Lab pt.2</title>
      <link>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/minihomelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 23:11:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/minihomelab/</guid>
      <description>This is an update pertaining to my last post. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve set up a couple useful services and built a primitive but dynamic landing page.
Setup All the services are running their own servers, each listening on a different port. The landing page is powered by Node.js listening on port 80 and has links to everything else. Since some of the services are data intensive, I&amp;rsquo;ve set up the landing page to display current disk usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac Mini Home Lab</title>
      <link>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/macmini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 11:27:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/macmini/</guid>
      <description>Recently, a family member replaced her aging 2012 Mac Mini with a custom gaming rig. Since then, it&amp;rsquo;s been lying around, and because it&amp;rsquo;s a decently specced machine for its time (Ivy Bridge i7, 8GB RAM) I figured maybe there&amp;rsquo;s some use I can put it to.
The main reasons for replacing it were lack of graphics power and it was extremely sluggish due to its old 5400rpm 2.5&amp;quot; HDD. However, CPU performance is still in perfectly usable realms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The elusive perfect setup</title>
      <link>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/setups/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 23:46:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/setups/</guid>
      <description>In the last few years, I have spent a lot of effort trying to find a nice computing setup. I&amp;rsquo;ve finally converged on something that I am pretty content with, at least right now during COVID and WFH. Of course, everybody has different needs, as a CS student I personally need a system that lets me take (preferably digital) handwritten notes and write code. With COVID, I also went back to playing video games more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooking 101</title>
      <link>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/cooking101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 17:28:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/cooking101/</guid>
      <description>This one&amp;rsquo;s for anyone just getting started with cooking.
While I&amp;rsquo;m far from a master chef myself, I can in fact throw down a decently delicious dinner for a few guests. I realize that&amp;rsquo;s not too impressive in itself, but it&amp;rsquo;s far from where I was when I started college. Trust me. Back then the standards set by my cooking skills were so low that I was legitimately hyped when I treated myself to some McDonald&amp;rsquo;s takeaway for dinner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021</title>
      <link>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/newyear21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 18:30:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/newyear21/</guid>
      <description>The new year is a reflective period for many people, but this year I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to set my goals differently than I usually do. Firstly I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to figure out what my values currently are, then I came up with a bunch of ways to implement those values, and finally I selected the most promising ones to form the basis for concrete goals. Because it gets into the why and not just the what, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this approach will yield better results!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading NFC tags with SwiftUI</title>
      <link>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/ios-nfc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 18:58:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/ios-nfc/</guid>
      <description>I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a concise tutorial on CoreNFC&amp;rsquo;s NFCTagReader, so here goes nothing.
Prerequisites  You will need an Apple developer account Add the NFC capability to your project (in Signing &amp;amp; Capabilites, click the plus sign in the corner) Add a NFC Scan Usage Description to your Info.plist  NFC overview Generally speaking there are two types of NFC devices: active (e.g. your smartphone) and passive (e.g. a simple NFC tag).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screwing around with Xbox One</title>
      <link>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/xbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 22:06:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ariezlabs.com/blog/xbox/</guid>
      <description>These are my notes on mucking around with my old Xbox One for a bit. I swapped the drive and thermal paste and did some amateurish performance measurements of the latter.
 Skip to #The upgrade for step-by-step instructions for upgrading your drive. Skip to #Thermal paste for the thermal paste upgrade  Context So I bought the original Xbox One in 2015 when it was on sale for like 200 bucks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
