<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on AriezLabs</title>
    <link>http://ariezlabs.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on AriezLabs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 16:58:53 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://ariezlabs.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cooking 101</title>
      <link>http://ariezlabs.com/blog/cooking101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 17:28:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ariezlabs.com/blog/cooking101/</guid>
      <description>This one&amp;rsquo;s for anyone just getting started with cooking.
While I&amp;rsquo;m far from a master chef myself, I can in fact throw down a decently delicious dinner for a few guests. I realize that&amp;rsquo;s not too impressive in itself, but it&amp;rsquo;s far from where I was when I started college. Trust me. Back then the standards set by my cooking skills were so low that I was legitimately hyped when I treated myself to some McDonald&amp;rsquo;s takeaway for dinner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021</title>
      <link>http://ariezlabs.com/blog/newyear21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 18:30:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ariezlabs.com/blog/newyear21/</guid>
      <description>The new year is a reflective period for many people, but this year I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to set my goals differently than I usually do. Firstly I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to figure out what my values currently are, then I came up with a bunch of ways to implement those values, and finally I selected the most promising ones to form the basis for concrete goals. Because it gets into the why and not just the what, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this approach will yield better results!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading NFC tags with SwiftUI</title>
      <link>http://ariezlabs.com/blog/ios-nfc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 18:58:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ariezlabs.com/blog/ios-nfc/</guid>
      <description>I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a concise tutorial on CoreNFC&amp;rsquo;s NFCTagReader, so here goes nothing.
Prerequisites  You will need an Apple developer account Add the NFC capability to your project (in Signing &amp;amp; Capabilites, click the plus sign in the corner) Add a NFC Scan Usage Description to your Info.plist  NFC overview Generally speaking there are two types of NFC devices: active (e.g. your smartphone) and passive (e.g. a simple NFC tag).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screwing around with Xbox One</title>
      <link>http://ariezlabs.com/blog/xbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 22:06:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ariezlabs.com/blog/xbox/</guid>
      <description>These are my notes on mucking around with my old Xbox One for a bit. I swapped the drive and thermal paste and did some amateurish performance measurements of the latter.
 Skip to #The upgrade for step-by-step instructions for upgrading your drive. Skip to #Thermal paste for the thermal paste upgrade  Context So I bought the original Xbox One in 2015 when it was on sale for like 200 bucks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
